Downloaded from MoviesMod.at
[popping]
[soft rustling]
[KAGAYA]
Within the next five days,
Muzan will come.
I will be the bait you use.
When he comes,
I need you to behead him.
Master, what leads you
to believe he'll find you?
[Kagaya chuckles weakly]
My intuition. That's all.
Nothing beyond that.
But listen,
the others can't know.
They would never agree
to using me as bait like this.
They would sooner die
than do it.
You're the only one
that I can ask, Gyomei.
Even if you behead him,
he won't die.
♪
There's likely only one way
to destroy Muzan.
Trapping him in place
until sunlight shines upon him.
If beheading isn't enough
to kill him,
there's only one option left.
You all must endure a battle
until the sun rises.
Yes, sir.
If that is your wish,
then so be it, Master.
[KAGAYA] Thank goodness.
Gyomei, after I have perished,
please do not let
any more of my children
be sent to their graves.
That is my wish.
[♪ tense music playing]
[MUZAN] You think
you've driven me into a corner
with your little plan?
But you are all about to be
going straight to hell!
Mark my words, Demon Slayers.
I'll massacre every one of you
before sunrise!
[grunts angrily]
[Nakime plucking biwa strings]
You're the only one
going to hell!
And you won't get away!
Oh, is that so?
Let's see you try.
Tanjiro Kamado!
[rumbling]
I will defeat you!
Muzan Kibutsuji!
DEMON SLAYER: KIMETSU NO YAIBA
THE MOVIE: INFINITY CASTLE
[♪ opening theme song playing]
What is this place?
Everything's upside down.
KILL
Was all of this made using
the enemy's Blood Demon Art?
I don't understand
what's happening,
except that Ms. Tamayo
was restraining Muzan.
Even so, how long
can she keep that up?
[screaming]
[IGURO] Calm down, Kanroji.
[gasps] Yes!
[IGURO] Stay with me.
[gasps]
[Gyomei grunts]
[effort grunts]
[TANJIRO] I need to reach Muzan
as soon as possible
and defeat him
by whatever means!
[grunts]
[♪ Gregorian chanting]
That's the bottom!
I'll be killed at this speed!
I'll use a move
to change directions.
Then find something
to grab on to.
DESTROY
[♪ music intensifies]
It didn't work. I can't
break away from this free fall.
DESTROYER OF DEMONS
[♪ low tense music playing]
[♪ music fades]
[Tanjiro panting]
[GIYU] You all right?
Yes. Thanks for your help.
[sighs in relief]
You really saved--
Water Breathing, First Form:
Water Surface Slash.
[GIYU] Tanjiro!
[♪ intense music playing]
[hinges creaking]
[snarling]
[BOTH] Water Breathing.
[TANJIRO] Sixth Form.
[GIYU] Third Form.
[TANJIRO] Whirlpool!
[GIYU] Flowing Dance.
[Tanjiro groans nervously]
Mr. Giyu's amazing.
He can tell exactly which move
I'm gonna use.
Then he follows up with one
that prevents
any kind of friendly fire.
He's unbelievable.
Just what's behind those eyes?
[stifled whimpering]
If I'm not mistaken...
this is the place
that Shinazugawa and Iguro
mentioned.
[♪ Gregorian chanting]
Which means
Kibutsuji's plan
was to gather everyone here,
then kill us all
in one fell swoop.
From here on out, we'll need
to be even more vigilant.
Right.
- Let's go.
- Right!
PITTER PATTER
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[demons snarling]
[IGURO]
Serpent Breathing, Fifth Form:
Slithering Serpent!
You demon scum!
Stay away from Kanroji!
[squealing]
Mr. Iguro is so cool!
- Are you hurt?
- No, not at all!
- Then, let's go.
- Okay!
[Kanroji squealing]
[grunts]
Tokito!
[demons snarling]
[MUICHIRO] There's a whole lot
of demons, huh?
[GYOMEI] It would seem
they've been given
the strength of the Lower Ranks.
It's clear that they're being
used to try and exhaust us.
[metallic rattling]
[MUICHIRO] Hmm.
What of the Master?
[GYOMEI] He has departed
from this world.
It was a truly noble end.
Knowing him,
he never would have allowed
himself to be caught unawares.
Did he sacrifice himself?
[GYOMEI] Indeed. The Master
did not have much time left.
[MUICHIRO] Master.
Back when I was mortally wounded
by a demon
and found myself
teetering on the edge
between life and death...
...he stayed by my side.
He did the same
for every Corps member
who was on the brink of death.
Like a father.
[GYOMEI] Yes, I know.
[MUICHIRO] Muzan not only
took my brother from me,
but our father as well.
That bastard.
Damn him!
I swear I'll make him suffer.
I'll send him straight to hell!
[GYOMEI] You're not alone.
Trust me, we all feel the same.
DESTROY
[SHINAZUGAWA]
Forgive me, Master.
I couldn't protect you.
[distorted grunting]
[blade rasps]
[♪ upbeat music playing]
There's no end
to you lowlifes, huh?
[demon cackling]
That's just fine by me.
I'll kill all of you!
[INOSUKE] Hyah!
Make way! I'm coming through!
[chuckles]
Whole lotta falling
happening here!
Hyah! Pretty rude to just
drop me in here out of nowhere!
Though I've been itching to see
how my training's paying off.
So with that in mind,
let's test it out on you chubs!
[chuckles]
Let's go!
[grunting]
[Genya panting]
Where am I?
The Demon Headquarters?
Where are the others?
Big Brother.
I hope you're safe, too.
[ZENITSU] I just heard a sound.
Could it be that
he's somewhere nearby?
[demons snarling]
You'll regret this.
I won't forgive you.
Not in a million years.
♪
[SHINOBU] I smell blood.
What is this place?
[chomping]
[DEMON] Hmm?
Oh, my. You're here.
UPPER TWO
Oh! And you're a girl, too!
What a young and tasty morsel
we have. [chuckles]
I'll have to properly thank
Nakime for this later.
[Shinobu panting]
[whimpers softly]
[KANAE] Shinobu.
You must leave
the Demon Slayer Corps.
I know that
you've trained really hard
and you're fighting
to make a difference.
- [sobbing softly]
- But I don't think you'll...
[sighs softly]
[stifled sobbing]
I want you to live the life
of a happy, normal girl.
To be able to see
your own hair turn gray.
DESTROYER OF DEMONS
Really... you've done enough.
[SHINOBU] No! [sobbing]
Can't stop now!
I will avenge you
if it's the last thing I do!
This demon! I need to know...
I have to know
what it looked like!
Please, Big Sister,
I'm begging you!
Tell me!
I could never live a normal life
knowing someone did this to you!
[sobbing] Please!
[sighs weakly]
[KANAE] It was a demon
with a blood-stained pattern
on his head.
[DEMON] I must say, it's very
nice to meet you, miss.
You may refer to me as Doma.
Ah, what a wonderful night!
[SHINOBU] Such a warm smile
and gentle voice.
There's a soft,
benevolent presence to him.
[woman weakly] Please, help me.
Please help me!
Shh.
Can't you see that
we're talking?
Hmm?
[SHINOBU] Are you all right?
[DOMA] Wow!
That was fast.
Are you a Hashira?
[labored breathing]
[squelching]
- [gasps]
- [♪ unsettling music playing]
[DOMA]
Oh, don't worry about that.
You can just leave her
right there.
I'll make
a proper meal of her later.
[exhales]
And this demon...
the weapon he used,
it was a pair of sharp fans.
[metallic scraping]
As the founder
of the Eternal Paradise Faith,
it is my sworn duty to see that
all my followers
attain happiness.
I'll be sure
to consume her completely.
[SHINOBU] There's no doubt.
This is the demon
who killed my sister.
Attaining happiness?
For who exactly?
This girl was horrified,
crying out for help.
- And that's why I saved her.
- [fans scraping]
Her suffering
has come to an end.
No more pain.
No more fear.
Everyone is afraid of death.
So I help them
by consuming them.
This way, they get to live on
within me for all eternity.
I take in their entire being.
Blood. Desires.
Even the last bit of their sinew
- and help their souls transcend.
- [♪ unsettling music playing]
What you're spouting
is sheer nonsense.
And to say it with such glee...
You truly make me sick!
Aw.
I can't believe you'd say that
after we'd only just met.
Oh, I see.
Oh, you poor thing.
Did something unfortunate
happen?
Let's hear it.
Go on, tell me.
"Unfortunate" doesn't begin
to describe it!
You are the one who killed
my big sister, weren't you?
Does the haori I'm wearing
mean nothing to you?!
Huh?
♪
[blade rasps]
[flesh squelching]
[DOMA] That's right.
It belonged to the girl
who used Flower Breathing.
Such a sweet, gentle child.
The sun came up
and cut our time short.
I remember.
It's a shame I didn't get-- Her.
[SHINOBU] Insect Breathing,
Dance of the Bee Sting:
True Flutter.
A marvelous thrust.
I hardly even saw it.
Blood Demon Art:
Frozen Lotus.
[Shinobu shivering] So cold.
It feels like my lungs
are bursting.
[DOMA] Hmm.
Look at that. You are fast.
Unfortunately for you,
those thrusts aren't enough
to kill a demon.
[slurps]
[rattling]
Aim for here.
You need to chop off my head.
DESTROY
My thrusts alone
may not be enough,
but what of this?
- [clanks]
- [ratchets, clicks]
[Doma groans]
[SHINOBU] Time to see
whether this toxin
works on an Upper Rank.
Sister, lend me
your strength, please.
[retches]
[straining] This poison.
It's clearly far stronger
than the strain you used
up on Rui's mountain. [wheezing]
[SHINOBU] So they did
exchange information.
This is the drawback
to using poison.
[DOMA] He told me that
you've been changing concoction
for each demon you face.
[straining]
- [coughs, retches]
- [blood splatters]
[wheezing]
Oh, my.
It would seem that I've already
neutralized all of your poison.
How rude of me.
And after you'd made it
just for me.
That sword of yours,
it makes quite an interesting
sound when you sheathe it.
Is that where you change
what poison you use?
Yay! This is fun!
Who knew being poisoned
was so invigorating?
It's almost addictive.
What will the next formula
be like? [chuckles]
Come on, let's give it a try.
- [swishing]
- [rattling]
Very well then,
I'll oblige.
See...
...I'd already anticipated
this would happen.
[Doma chuckling]
Is your next batch set?
I'm ready whenever you are.
I know I just said
to give it a try...
...but you could at least
change up your offense.
- [metallic clanking]
- [Doma chuckles]
- [continues chuckling]
- [grunts]
What's this?
You seem to be
slower than earlier.
So sad.
[SHINOBU] Insect Breathing,
Dance of the Horsefly:
Enticing Slash!
Oh, my.
You were able to land a hit.
The way you got through
all my defenses,
it's amazing!
I'm truly impressed.
It's almost enough
to bring a tear to my eye.
Come on,
what are you waiting for?
Hurry up and attack me again,
before I stop the poison.
Please? You're doing so well.
Maybe the next attack kills me.
[disgruntled sigh]
[laughs] Yes! That's the spirit!
Ever since I was a child,
I was kind and clever.
I always helped those
who were in need
and led them
to the path of happiness.
It was my duty after all.
[DOMA'S FATHER] His eyes
have the colors of a rainbow.
And this gray hair
is proof of his innocence.
This child is truly special.
Surely he can hear
the voices of the gods.
[♪ slow piano notes playing]
[DOMA] My parents were
hopelessly naive simpletons.
You'd have to be
in order to found a religion
like the Eternal Paradise Faith.
I pitied them,
so I always played along
with their make-believe ideas.
I never once heard
the voice of the gods.
At first, I didn't know
how to deal
with the hordes of people
worshiping and praying to me.
Seeing these grown-ups
come crying to a child
saying they were suffering,
pleading for help,
made me worry
if they were sick in the head.
After nearly putting me to sleep
with their personal stories,
they would bow to me,
asking to be guided to paradise.
I cried.
"You poor things," I thought.
"Paradise doesn't even exist.
It's just a fairy tale
concocted by deluded humans.
There are no gods or Buddhas."
These people
had lived for decades,
yet they still couldn't grasp
that simple truth.
When you die,
you return to nothingness.
All feeling ceases.
Your heart stops.
Your brain stops.
You rot and return to the earth.
Such is the fate
of every living creature.
To be too foolish
to accept reality,
what a hard life that must be.
I want to bring happiness
to these pitiful people.
I want to save them.
I truly believe
that is my purpose here.
[squelches]
[blade rasps]
- Aw. Still nothing.
- [metallic rattling]
And that was number five.
What will you do?
The toxin's
getting less effective.
How many more times
do you think you can adapt it?
- Oh! Are you out of breath now?
- [panting]
Look at all that sweat.
Are you all right?
[SHINOBU] So, this is the power
of an Upper Rank.
None of my poisons are working.
He's adapting too fast
to keep up with.
Your alveoli must be dead now.
[crystals tinkling]
Painful.
You did breathe it in,
my Blood Demon Art.
[SHINOBU] He turns
his frozen blood into mist
and disperses it with his fans.
Even breathing around him
is dangerous now.
[clangs]
[ratchets, clicks]
This time, I'll increase
the dose with multiple strikes!
Insect Breathing,
Dance of the Dragonfly:
♪
Compound Eye Hexagon!
I can't believe it!
Such blazing speed!
You might be the fastest Hashira
I've ever met.
- [blood squelches]
- [gasps]
[SHINOBU] He... got me.
[grunts]
Forget the poison.
Why not try to decapitate me?
With your speed,
you might have won.
[laughs sarcastically]
Maybe not.
I mean, you are small.
[gasps, breathing shakily]
[SHINOBU] Why are my hands
so small? I wonder.
How come I was never able
to grow taller?
If my stature
were just a little bigger,
could I have been able to behead
and defeat a demon?
The longer
your arms and legs are,
the more muscles you have,
which means more strength
in your attacks.
[♪ tender music playing]
My sister
was also of small frame,
but she was taller than I.
How I envy Mr. Himejima.
Seeing someone like him
come to the rescue
would give anyone relief.
I know what my sister
really wanted to say,
but didn't have the heart to.
[DOMA] Oh, no!
Have our games come to an end?
That's too bad.
[metallic rattling]
[SHINOBU] "I don't think
you'll win against that demon."
[voice breaking] That's what
you were going to say.
But you stopped yourself,
didn't you?
[KANAE] Pull yourself together.
This is no time for tears.
[SHINOBU] Sister.
[KANAE] Stand up.
[SHINOBU] I can't.
I've lost so much blood.
My left lung is punctured
and I can't even breathe.
You can and you will.
Stand up.
You are a Hashira, Shinobu.
[grunting softly]
If you've made up your mind
to defeat him, then do so.
No excuses.
Win by whatever means you can.
Remember your promise,
to me and Kanao.
[SHINOBU] Kanao.
[DOMA] Forgive me.
You must be suffering right now.
[whimpering softly]
[gasps]
I know that you have it in you.
Do your best.
- Huh?
- [metallic rattling]
[quivers]
Wait. Are you... standing up?
[exclaims in amazement]
Scary.
Are you actually a human?
I slashed your collarbone,
your lungs, and your ribs.
At your diminutive size
and the amount of blood
you've lost,
how are you not dead right now?
[coughs]
See? Right there.
There clearly is blood
gurgling in your lungs.
The pain must be unimaginable.
Surrender and I'll put an end
to your suffering.
It'll be quick.
It's too late for you.
So, just let go.
[SHINOBU] I'll make a go
for his neck this time
and put everything I have left
into this strike!
Insect Breathing,
Dance of the Centipede.
[DOMA] Hmm?
[SHINOBU]
Hundred-Legged Zigzag.
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[groans]
[DOMA] It feels like
she's everywhere at once.
Just her movement
destroyed the bridge.
[squeaking]
So fast. I can't follow her.
[impact grunts]
From below?
[gasps]
[Shinobu grunts]
- [glass shatters]
- [♪ music swells, fades]
[SHINOBU]
Back when I was a child...
...I thought of happiness
like a road,
one that stretched on
into the distance
with no end in sight.
[laughter]
[blood splatters]
It wasn't until it was destroyed
that I finally realized
the road beneath my feet
was but a thin sheet of glass.
♪
However, some haven't had
the glass broken yet.
All I wanted after being saved
was to become stronger...
...so that some day,
I could protect those people.
So... we made a promise.
To vanquish the demons
as many as we could, together.
[♪ poignant music playing]
In hopes that the pain
we suffered
would never be felt by another.
Even if I'm weak...
...even if I can't
decapitate demons,
if I can take down just one,
I can save dozens of lives.
And if that demon's
an Upper Rank,
it could mean saving hundreds.
It's not a matter
of can or cannot.
This is something I have to do.
Are you angry?
[SHINOBU] Yes.
I am angry, Tanjiro.
I'm furious.
In fact...
...I'm always angry.
How could I not be?
My parents were killed.
My older sister was killed.
My Tsuguko, other than Kanao,
were killed.
And those poor girls.
If it weren't for the demons...
If it weren't for the demons
that killed their loved ones,
they'd be living happily
with their families.
[♪ discordant music playing]
It's all so infuriating!
Stop messing with me, damn it!
Why the hell isn't my poison
working on this prick?
You bastard!
[exhales]
[ice crackling]
I'm moved! You did your best!
Even though you're so weak.
You must have worked
so incredibly hard
to get to this point. [sobbing]
You're weaker than your sister,
and yet, you somehow
outlived her.
[sniffles] It's a miracle
you survived this long.
[body cracking]
[coughs]
Even when hope is gone,
humans always fight
to the bitter end.
Humans are so foolish.
But that's what makes them
so beautiful.
I deem you worthy
of becoming part of me.
[sobbing] You and I
shall share eternity!
Do you have any last words?
I'm listening.
Rot in hell, you bastard!
[exclaims in horror] Master!
[bones crunching]
[exclaims in anguish]
[clangs]
[clatters]
[quivering]
[screaming in agony]
♪
[ZENITSU] I can't shake
the feeling he's here.
He must be.
He's got a score to settle
with me, too.
The people we love,
the people we hold dear
are so precious.
We take for granted
that they'll always be there.
However, that's just
a selfish delusion.
Flower Breathing...
[ZENITSU] Because the thought
of living without them
is simply unbearable.
...Fourth Form:
Crimson Hanagoromo!
[shatters]
[grunts]
[DOMA] Wow!
You nearly got me there.
[ZENITSU] "They'll always be
alive and close by."
It's a naive thought, I know,
but we all wanna believe it.
Would you mind holding off
your attacks for just a second?
- I'm trying to absorb her.
- [flesh squelching]
[seething]
[DOMA] How strange.
You're not taking the bait,
are you?
What she did earlier,
that motion she made
with her fingers.
Was that her warning you
of my powers?
I'm impressed she thought
to do that so quickly.
Good job you did it.
Too bad it doesn't matter.
- [flesh squelching]
- [clatters]
Well, in case
you were wondering,
your master was tastier
than I imagined.
[slurps]
And now, you're here.
It's just one feast
after another, it seems.
Ah, this truly is...
a wonderful night.
[seething]
You can't hide.
Come out.
Have some dignity and face me.
[DEMON] Sounds like someone
ought to teach you some manners.
Did you forget
that I'm your senior?
You look a little stronger
than the last time I saw ya.
It's too bad you still reek
of being a pathetic weakling.
[clatters]
UPPER SIX
It's been a while,
hasn't it... Zenitsu?
[chuckles]
[ZENITSU] Kaigaku.
You don't get my respect.
You're a demon.
You'll be treated as such.
[Nakime plucking biwa strings]
- [rumbles]
- [Tanjiro gasps]
[grunts]
Water Breathing, Ninth Form:
Splashing Water Flow, Turbulent!
[grunts]
Stay focused!
All right!
This place is insane.
The building keeps shifting
and rearranging itself
as if it's alive.
I can tell that
it's trying to separate us.
We have to regroup
with the other Corps members
and stay together
till we reach Muzan!
[cawing]
Attention!
Shinobu Kocho is dead!
She fought valiantly
against Upper Two
but was defeated!
- [gasps]
- [muted silence]
[♪ poignant music playing]
[inaudible laughter]
[seething]
[cawing]
[GIYU] Strange.
There's a piece of paper
wrapped around its neck.
How are the crows already here?
[♪ epic dramatic music playing]
Shinobu is dead,
but we must push forward.
Think only of what must be done
for victory.
[KUINA, KANATA] Right.
And what about the others?
I need reports
on their whereabouts.
[KANATA]
Center of the 40th vertical
and 12th horizontal levels.
[fight grunts]
The Corps members
are fighting off
what appears to be
at least ten demons.
[fight grunts]
However, more than 30 demons
are moving in their direction
from behind the walls.
[KIRIYA]
Using Mr. Yushiro's eyes,
we're able to see
Blood Demon Arts,
something that isn't possible
to do with the human eye.
Each red light
is a Blood Demon Art.
The more intense they glow,
the more potent their power.
In this place, the entire area,
buildings and all, must also be
a Blood Demon Art.
There's seemingly
no end in sight to it.
What incredible power!
A demon labyrinth
with the ability
to branch out endlessly.
And here we lie at its center,
trapped within the walls
of this infinite castle.
[KAKUSHI 1] This one's finished.
[KIRIYA] However, it's not as if
we've been caught off guard.
KAKUSHI
My father prepared
for this day meticulously.
With Gyomei's cooperation,
he had the Hashira
within arm's reach
to mobilize at any time.
To prevent the Corps members
from being isolated,
he sent the Kasugai Crows
to gather them into groups
and waited.
He enlisted the aid
of Ms. Tamayo and Mr. Yushiro.
And finally,
to ensure that
their plan would succeed,
my sisters and our parents
readily sacrificed their lives.
We cannot lose,
no matter what!
[♪ music intensifies]
Amongst the Blood Demon Arts,
there are five traces of power
that tower over the rest
as if flaunting their strength.
These must be Upper Ranks.
One of them is at the same spot
where Shinobu
was last seen fighting.
Found another!
Upper Six and Zenitsu have just
encountered each other!
An Upper Rank!
Is he alone?
[KUINA] He is.
It looks to be a one-on-one!
[KIRIYA] A Hinoe can't beat
an Upper Rank by themself.
Send backup!
[KAIGAKU] Hmm.
What, you're frozen in fear?
Guess some things never change.
Once a coward, always a coward.
Did you ever become a Hashira?
[scoffs] Guess not.
That's too bad.
Got any new techniques?
Or still just First Form?
For an Upper Rank bottom feeder
who's nothing more
than a spare blade,
you're sure acting
awfully proud.
[Kaigaku sarcastically]
Wow! [laughs]
Who taught you to talk
like that? New friends?
[ZENITSU] Why the hell
did you become a demon?
[laughs] You'd never understand.
You were supposed to succeed
Thunder Breathing!
But you tarnished it!
Huh?
[ZENITSU]
After you became a demon,
he...
He committed seppuku!
[♪ poignant music playing]
[voice breaking] Even worse,
he did it by himself.
He was all alone!
Because of that,
no one was there
to put him out of his misery.
He bled out
and died a painful death.
It's your fault!
Gramps died the most
agonizing death possible
all because
the Thunder Breathing rights
produced a demon!
Why the hell should I care?
Gramps died? So what?
Want me to cry?
Did you expect me
to give it to him?
Well, I don't.
In fact, I don't care for anyone
who doesn't appreciate me.
No matter what,
this is who I am.
Take the side
of whoever knows my worth.
[laughs]
If the old geezer
really did die in agony,
then I couldn't be happier.
I slaved away
for that ungrateful bastard.
And what does he do to repay me?
He makes you my co-successor
instead of just letting me
carry the torch!
I hope he rots!
Former Hashira or not,
I would never shed a tear
over some senile geezer.
[laughs boorishly]
[ZENITSU] Gramps knew
exactly what he was doing.
We were made co-successors
because we're weak.
I was only able to use
the First Form
while you could use
everything but First Form.
I can't help
but feel sorry for Gramps
that he has two
useless successors!
[KAIGAKU]
Don't lump us together!
I'm nothing like you!
Thunder Breathing, Fourth Form:
Distant Thunder!
[♪ intense dramatic music
playing]
[gasps]
You're so slow, scum.
- [groans]
- [blood splatters]
[KAIGAKU]
What the hell? He got me.
His speed is unreal.
He never moved like that.
He's changed.
But he's not the only one.
[wet squelching]
There's no shame in kneeling
down before the powerful
if it means surviving.
As long as you're alive,
you can still win.
Only once you die have you lost.
Even if you have to beg
on your hands and knees.
Even if you're without a home
and have to drink from a puddle.
Even if they condemn you
for stealing money.
As long as you're alive,
there's still a future
where you can win.
Believing that
is all that's kept me going.
[KOKUSHIBO]
Forfeit your humanity
and limitless power
will be within reach.
Should my Lord
choose to acknowledge you,
demon blood
shall course through your veins.
[Kaigaku quivers]
The stronger the swordsman,
the longer it takes for him
to become a demon.
It took me three days
to fully transform.
Turning a breathing technique
user into a demon
is no small feat.
Doing such a thing will require
an exorbitant amount
of my Lord's blood.
And though it is rare,
some people,
for whatever reason,
are physically incapable
of becoming demons.
Huh?
[KOKUSHIBO] I'm curious to see
how you will fare.
UPPER ONE
[quivers]
You must appreciate this blood.
Even holding it as you are now
is an honor you cannot fathom.
Should you spill a single drop,
I'll have you dismembered
in an instant
before it touches the ground.
[gasps in horror]
[breathing shakily]
[KAIGAKU] Even now,
I remember the terror I felt.
Like every cell in my body
was screaming in anguish.
Compared to what I felt then,
this is nothing.
- He's just a punk.
- [clatters]
He might be stronger,
but he's not on par
with an Upper Rank.
Zenitsu Agatsuma
is and always will be trash.
He's a despicable crybaby
without a shred of dignity
or valor!
Somebody, help!
I fell in a pitfall
and twisted my ankle!
[KAIGAKU] The disrespect!
As if I'd be co-successor
with that sniveling loser!
[JIGORO] Here you are, Kaigaku.
- [ZENITSU] Hey, Gramps?
- [KAIGAKU] Hmm?
It looks a little big on me,
don't you think?
- Maybe I'll grow into it...
- [KAIGAKU] I'm supposed to be
- that idiot's equal?
- [both laughing]
That's gotta be
some kind of sick joke!
[seething]
The old bastard deserved to die!
And if you miss him so dearly,
then I'll see to it
you join him!
[ZENITSU] I was only ever able
to learn the First Form.
However, you were able to learn
everything but the First Form.
[♪ tender music playing]
Gramps knew that.
His solution
was having us both succeed
the Thunder Breathing technique.
But you denied him that.
You became a demon
purely to reject him.
- [crackling]
- It's coming!
Thunder Breathing, Second Form:
Rice Spirit!
[♪ dramatic synth music playing]
[ZENITSU] He attacked five times
in one breath.
- [Kaigaku yells]
- [effort grunts, strains]
How many people
have you devoured?
You can't even tell right
from wrong anymore!
I'm more aware of those
than I've ever been!
What's the matter?
Aren't you supposed to be
the old geezer's favorite?
- [grunts]
- If you are,
then show me
what he passed down to you!
It's the only technique
you've got, so use it!
[Zenitsu grunts]
Go all out.
Use everything you got.
- [groans angrily]
- And don't you dare hold back
- for a second!
- [determined grunt]
[ZENITSU] Thunder Breathing...
...First Form...
[scoffs]
...Thunderclap and Flash.
[effort grunts]
[laughs boisterously]
As if a basic attack
like charging me head-on
would ever find its mark.
Don't make me laugh!
Thunder Breathing,
Third Form: Thunder Swarm!
[grunting]
[ZENITSU] He's attacking me
from every angle at once.
[KAIGAKU] What's the matter?
Don't tell me
you're done already!
[ZENITSU]
Thunder Breathing, First Form:
Thunderclap and Flash:
Eight Fold!
- That's not gonna work!
- [Zenitsu grunts]
Thunder Breathing, Fifth Form:
Heat Lightning!
- Ah!
- Gotcha!
How does the bite of my Blood
Demon Art-enhanced sword feel?
- [electricity crackling]
- Each strike on contact
leaves a wound
that burns your skin.
This proves those who recognize
my talents and value are right!
And those that dismiss
or condemn me are wrong!
Do you get it now?
This is the power I have!
My power as a demon that is!
All you know how to do
is use First Form,
yet that geezer chose
to make you his successor!
And, boy,
what a mistake that was!
So, that's it.
This is the path
that you've chosen to take.
[weakly] I already knew.
I knew, but...
[sword scraping]
With this strike, I'll end this.
You're finished!
- [crackling]
- Thunder Breathing...
- [rumbling]
- ...Sixth Form:
- [crackling]
- [♪ music intensifies]
Rumble and Flash!
That strike I landed will keep
crackling through your flesh!
This is the power that I gained
by becoming a demon.
Get it now?
I've long surpassed
Thunder Breathing!
[laughs boisterously]
You and I aren't equals.
And we never have been.
I'm better than all of you.
Guess the old bastard
shouldn't have put
his trust in you after all.
[laughs boisterously]
[JIGORO] Come on,
be more like Kaigaku!
He's your senior,
so follow his example, you hear?
Hang on. Isn't the First Form
pretty much the entire basis
of Thunder Breathing?
Yeah, and it's the only one
he can't do.
You know what that means,
don't ya?
That even though
he's mastered other forms,
he's still a weakling.
Yep, exactly.
The way he shows off, though?
He's got such an ego.
[BOY 1] No way
he becomes a Hashira.
[BOY 2] Yeah,
he'll die before then.
[♪ gentle music playing]
What did I do to deserve that?
I heard you went and punched
someone from a higher rank.
Don't go around making trouble,
you trash!
It's embarrassing even being
seen in the same room as you.
[ZENITSU] I was fully aware
that you hated me, Kaigaku.
And to be perfectly honest,
I hated you, too.
Even so, I couldn't help
but respect you as well.
You never stopped
working towards your goals.
Despite our differences,
I looked up to you
as an example.
You really were a special guy.
It wasn't just me.
Gramps thought
you were remarkable, too.
But I guess you weren't
satisfied with that, were you?
No matter the day,
the only sound that came
from you was discontent.
[soft tinkling]
It was like the box
where you kept your joy
had a hole in it.
And that joy kept leaking out.
If the hole isn't mended,
happiness will always be
out of reach.
Gramps,
I'm sorry we're fighting...
...but he and I
must walk separate paths.
- [clangs]
- [crackling]
[KAIGAKU] Huh?
He's still holding on?
[electricity crackling]
[♪ synth music playing]
[power surging]
What the hell?
[ZENITSU] Brother...
- ...I'm sorry.
- [gasps]
[♪ music intensifies]
Thunder Breathing, Seventh Form:
[roaring]
God of Fire Thunder.
[KAIGAKU] That...
was so fast.
That move. What was it?
Unbelievable.
How come I've never seen
that technique until now?
Damn you. Damn you!
I always knew that stupid geezer
liked you more than me!
Why else would he only
teach you that technique?!
You're wrong.
[gasps]
[♪ gentle music playing]
[ZENITSU] Gramps was never
that kind of person.
This technique
is something I made.
I created it all by myself.
My hope was...
...that one day, I'd be able
to use it to fight by your side.
[KAIGAKU]
How is this even possible?
Thunder Breathing
only has six techniques,
and yet he was able
to create a seventh?
Him? The one who can only
use the First Form?
He's inferior to me
in every way!
[groans angrily]
I can't accept it.
I won't accept it!
This must be
some kind of twisted joke!
Someone like me losing to him?
I must be going insane!
Wait!
With his strength depleted,
I can still have the last laugh.
This fall will kill him
and he can't stop it.
I'll be taking him to hell
with me.[laughs maliciously]
[YUSHIRO]
Those who never give to others
are never able to receive
in return.
Huh?
People who have
nothing but desire
are no different than those
who have nothing at all.
And one cannot create anything
out of nothing.
Dying alone is pathetic,
wouldn't you say?
[screaming in anguish]
[fizzles out]
[gasps]
- [birds chirping]
- [leaves rustling]
Where am I?
- [stream trickling]
- [birds chirping]
[gasps]
Gramps!
[♪ tender music playing]
I'm sorry!
I... I couldn't get along
with Kaigaku!
I even tried
writing him letters, but...
But he never wrote me back.
And... [sobs]
...if it weren't for me,
he might not have ended up
the way he did.
I'm really sorry!
Forgive me!
I wasn't able to pay you back
for everything!
I really wanted you
to see me as a Hashira,
to make you proud.
I'm sorry.
I failed you, Gramps!
[sobbing] I understand
if you hate me now.
Please, just say something.
Anything!
[effort grunting]
Damn it! What's this
grabbing my leg?
Gramps! I just...
I need-- [grunts]
Damn it!
[effort grunting]
[JIGORO] Zenitsu.
[Zenitsu gasps softly]
Listen to me, lad.
You are my pride and joy.
[♪ music fades]
[MURATA] Well? Can you save him?
He's someone that I know.
I can't watch him die.
Please tell me there's a way!
Keep your voice down.
You're not helping.
Just watch out
for enemy ambushes.
At least then you'll actually be
doing something useful.
[grunting angrily]
Excuse me? And just
who the hell are you, huh?
I better not find out
you're a lower rank than I am!
I'm a demon. I don't care
about your hierarchy.
This'll slow
the Blood Demon Art.
But if these cracks
keep spreading,
it'll travel all the way
to his eyes.
Hey, can you hear me?
[groans]
[all three exclaim]
Your bedside manner
really sucks, you know that?
I'm also using a hemostatic,
but I still can't get
the bleeding to stop.
What did I say?!
Don't listen to him.
You're gonna be fine.
I swear
you'll pull through this!
Yeah, you can do it!
Fight on! Fight on!
The only reason
you're alive right now
is because
the Upper Rank you fought
still hadn't mastered
his own techniques.
That was lucky for you.
If you'd fought him
a year from now,
you would have died instantly.
[Murata groaning]
Could you stop
with the doom and gloom?
Consider his feelings!
[breathing heavily]
Hey, don't pretend like
I'm the one in the wrong here.
What? What are you pointing at?
[YUSHIRO] Your screaming let
the demons know we're here.
[all screaming]
Don't say I didn't warn you.
[snarling]
Hey, it was Yushiro, right?
Take care of Agatsuma!
- Charge!
- [all grunting]
Murata, please take care of them
quickly, okay?
I'm gonna give you
such an earful later!
- Damn.
- [demon snarling]
Water Breathing, Second Form:
Water Wheel! [yells]
We're gonna head them off.
Follow my lead, everyone!
[all yelling]
- [footsteps receding]
- [grunts]
[♪ foreboding music playing]
This is bad.
They're gonna run into "him."
[TANJIRO] We haven't encountered
any Upper Ranks.
Are we still that far
from Muzan?
I hope the others are all right.
Miss Shinobu...
we're going to win this battle.
For you. For everyone!
- [loud crash]
- [gasps]
That jolt! What was that?
Mr. Giyu!
Stay there!
- Keep calm.
- [grunts]
[TANJIRO]
Is someone else fighting?
Are we about to lose
another comrade?
- [♪ intriguing music playing]
- [loud thuds]
No, it's something else.
And it's coming this way.
[sniffs]
This... This scent.
[GIYU] Above us!
Get back, Tanjiro!
[grunts]
[DEMON] Long time no see.
It's commendable
you got this far.
Especially for a puny insect.
UPPER THREE
Don't you agree, Tanjiro?!
[Tanjiro seething]
Akaza!
[♪ low tense music playing]
[heavy burbling]
[breathing heavily]
[TAMAYO] This place...
If I had to guess,
this fleshy cocoon
is breaking down
and disposing the drug
that's rescinding
his demon form.
Muzan Kibutsuji,
I had sworn to destroy you
by any means necessary.
Yet, at this moment,
I am powerless to do so.
[loud thump]
[grunting]
Soon enough,
I'll be absorbed as well.
Please, someone. Anyone!
Come quickly!
I beg you!
[fight grunts]
[♪ intense music playing]
[KIRIYA] According to Father,
if Muzan should die,
the other demons
will also perish.
By that logic, it's clear
that Muzan is still alive.
At this very moment,
Ms. Tamayo must be
suppressing his powers.
If she weren't,
he would surely be aware
of Yushiro's watchful gaze.
Before Muzan's powers
are fully restored,
we must do whatever it takes
to see that he's defeated.
I have to wonder, though,
inside of this
infinite castle...
...will we really
be able to find him
and put an end to it all?
No need to be nervous.
You're doing a fine job,
my child.
Muzan will surely reveal himself
once more,
just as he did when he found me.
When it comes to this man,
that's simply his nature.
[gasps]
[KIRIYA] I understand, Father.
I will see to it
our plan succeeds.
We must find him before
the Corps members' strength
is fully depleted,
and settle this
once and for all.
[Gyomei grunts]
[distorted grunting]
- [grunting]
- [KAKUSHI 1] Protect them!
[KAKUSHI 2] Everybody, group up!
We have to form a wall!
Get their attention
off the Hashira!
Please, sir!
Go on ahead without us!
You as well! We got this!
Are you certain?
- [both grunting]
- [groans]
[thuds]
We are!
Just defeat Kibutsuji!
Please, sir!
Very well, then.
I will put my faith
in your efforts here.
Tokito!
[KAKUSHI 1] All right!
Let's show them the fruits
of our Hashira training!
[ALL] Right!
[♪ epic cinematic music playing]
[fight grunts]
[KIRIYA] Everyone, thank you.
I know Father would be proud
to see you giving it your all.
[♪ melancholic music playing]
- [whimpering]
- [KIRIYA] Stop that!
You must keep your hands moving.
Right now, we need to focus.
[KANATA] Yes.
Master Kiriya
is quite impressive.
It's clear
he's still in mourning
over the loss of the Master,
yet his duty is unwavering.
He's led the Demon Slayer Corps
rather splendidly.
Wouldn't you agree, Mr. Rengoku?
I would, indeed.
These children
are still young in years,
but their resolve
is anything but childish.
I swear to protect them.
Just as Kyojuro did before me,
I will risk my own life
to do so.
[Nezuko whimpers in pain]
[SAKONJI] I didn't think
she would suffer this much.
The Master was working
with a demon named Tamayo
who delivered this antidote.
I've administered it
as she instructed.
Even so,
will Nezuko be able to turn
back into a human, I wonder?
If Nezuko
does become human again,
Muzan's grand scheme
will collapse.
His thousand-year quest
for a vessel
which can resist the sun
will be no more.
And all of the progress
he's made
will be wound back like a clock.
In the many years that we've had
to endure this nightmare,
Nezuko is the only demon
who has been able
to live in the sunlight.
[♪ melancholic music playing]
[heart beating]
[inhales deeply]
[sighs wearily]
"The final battle."
These words
echo in my mind.
[gulps, sighs]
And each time they do,
I can't help but tremble
as my heart beats louder.
This battle may finally
reach its conclusion tonight.
I never dreamed that I'd be
alive to witness it myself.
Tanjiro,
I sometimes
think back to the day
when you brought
your demon sister to me.
Ever since then,
it feels like a giant wheel
of fate has been slowly turning.
Perhaps it would be best to
compare the sum of our battles
to a giant dormant machine.
You and Nezuko are the small
cogs that have joined together
and awoken it from its slumber.
What was once frozen in place
has now been set into motion.
[♪ intriguing music playing]
- [moaning]
- Don't give up, Nezuko.
Keep up the fight, Tanjiro.
You both have to pull through,
no matter what!
[TANJIRO] Hinokami Kagura:
Fire Wheel!
[♪ epic dramatic music playing]
Go through!
If I can't even sever his arm,
I'll never sever his head!
[yelling]
[flesh squelches]
[blood splatters]
DESTROY
I got one.
I was able
to dodge his attack, too.
I can do this!
I couldn't aim for his head,
but this time, for sure!
Hinokami Kagura: Fake Rainbow!
[fizzles out]
[high-pitched ringing]
- [panting]
- [sword clatters]
[flesh squelching]
Huh?
[GIYU] Tanjiro.
You've really sharpened
your skills, haven't you?
It wouldn't be an exaggeration
to say he's at the level
of a Hashira now.
To think that he'd do this well
against Upper Three.
[♪ enchanting folk music
playing]
That day...
...I remember a boy
who felt completely helpless
as he collapsed
onto the cold snow,
begging through tears
for his sister's life.
But you are helpless no longer.
You have the strength
to fight not only for your life,
but also
for what's precious to you.
[AKAZA] "This boy is not weak.
Don't insult him."
I must admit that Kyojuro
was right when he said that.
You are certainly not weak.
In fact, I commend you.
Technique Development...
[♪ intense rock music playing]
Now, let's kick things off,
shall we?
It's time we had some fun.
- [rumbling]
- [heavy creaking]
[exhales sharply]
[grunts]
[GIYU]
Water Breathing, Third Form:
Flowing Dance!
You're a Water Hashira.
How lucky for me!
It's been 50 years
since I fought one.
[debris clattering]
Destructive Death: Disorder!
Water Breathing, Eleventh Form:
Dead Calm.
[AKAZA] I've never seen
that move before.
Perhaps the last
Water Hashira I killed
never had a chance to use it!
[TANJIRO] Hinokami Kagura:
Raging Sun!
He vanished!
Behind me!
Fake Rain Kagura!
[GIYU] Water Breathing,
Second Form: Water Wheel.
[yells]
[TANJIRO] Hinokami Kagura:
Flame Dance!
[AKAZA] Destructive Death,
Leg Type: Crown Splitter!
[TANJIRO]
I blocked it with my sword.
His move barely grazed me
and still did
this kind of damage?
[AKAZA] How marvelous!
That elegant sword skill
you're using is magnificent!
I must know now.
What is your name?
I want to remember you!
I don't have a name
to give to a demon like you.
I hate talking,
so don't speak to me!
Is that so?
You're not much
for small talk, are you?
Well, I happen to quite
enjoy it, so I'll ask you again.
What is your name?
[grunting]
- [impact grunts]
- [crumbles]
[AKAZA]
Destructive Death, Leg Type:
Explosive Flurry!
[yelling]
- [impact grunts]
- [TANJIRO] Mr. Giyu!
I see. That's his name.
Thank you for letting me know.
Hinokami Kagura!
Destructive Death:
Eight-Layered Demon Core!
Burning Bones, Summer Sun!
[panting]
[AKAZA] Excellent form!
To improve this much in such
a short time is impressive.
I'll give you my praise.
It seems obvious to me
that Kyojuro must have
really inspired you.
The night we met, you were
merely a weak, mournful child,
crumpled on the ground.
Not even worthy of being killed.
- But just look at you now!
- [cracking]
This leap in your abilities,
it's like you've been reborn!
My heart won't stop racing.
I'm truly overjoyed!
[snickers]
The night Kyojuro died,
I was glad that it happened.
[exclaims in disbelief]
How tragic would it have been
if he had never gotten
any stronger.
Such a stubborn man,
not letting go
of those worthless values
of staying human.
How dare you!
Shut up! Just shut up!
Don't you dare
even speak his name!
[AKAZA] What's the matter?
I'm only paying the man
a compliment.
I'm being sincere.
These are high words of praise.
[TANJIRO] You're wrong.
All you're doing
is insulting him!
You're just spitting
on his memory!
On all of us!
You couldn't be
more wrong, Tanjiro.
As you'll recall, the only thing
I despise is weak human beings.
Only a feeble weakling
is deserving of my scorn
and no one else.
That's right.
The mere sight of them
makes my skin crawl.
They make me retch!
Through the laws of nature,
they are weeded out
from this world
just as they should be.
Everything you just said
is wrong!
[AKAZA] Huh?
The fact
you're even alive right now,
isn't that proof enough?
As an infant,
we're all helpless.
We can't live
without someone else's help.
You're no different, Akaza.
Even if you don't remember,
there was a time
when you were protected
and cared for by someone.
I know it!
That's why you're alive.
The strong should aid
and protect the weak.
And in turn,
the weak become strong
and aid and protect
those weaker than themselves!
That is the law of nature.
Akaza, I can't tolerate
your way of thinking.
Here on out,
I won't let you
do as you please!
[AKAZA] I get it now.
I have a disgust for this boy
that's almost primal in nature.
Even if he's stronger,
that feeling hasn't faded.
[MAN] No matter who they are,
everyone begins life
as a newborn.
We learn by getting help
from those around us.
We are not competing
with others.
The only opponent
you have in life is yourself.
Just focus on becoming stronger
than you were yesterday.
If you can stay this path
for a decade or even two,
that would be commendable.
And before you know it,
you will be helping others
in turn.
[breathing shakily]
[gasps]
[TANJIRO] What was that?
He just swung his fist
at nothing.
Tanjiro.
You still repulse me to my core.
[♪ rock music playing]
Destructive Death,
Crushing Type:
Ten Thousand Leaves
Flashing Willow!
[TANJIRO]
This speed, it's blinding!
No, it's not just his speed.
It's his precision,
his aura, and also--
[grunts]
Destructive Death, Leg Type.
[TANJIRO] Below.
[AKAZA] Flying Planet
Thousand Wheels!
[TANJIRO] Even if I could
anticipate his strikes,
they're so powerful,
I can't completely deflect them.
His techniques are so precise,
they can pierce through any
opening, no matter how small.
It's like a magnet
is attracting his attacks
straight toward my weak points.
But how? What's happening?
What could be
causing this behavior?
Come on. Think.
What's the answer?!
There must be a clue
in what Akaza's said or done.
[Akaza grunts] Hyah!
[TANJIRO] Hinokami Kagura:
Solar Heat Haze!
[blood spurts]
[chuckles]
What an interesting move.
I dodged it at first, but then
the blade seemed to extend.
I don't know what kind of swing
you put behind it,
but the tip of your blade
wavered
like it was in a heat haze.
How fascinating!
- [grunts]
- [glass shattering]
[debris crumbling]
[TANJIRO]
Hinokami Kagura: Dance!
[clangs]
My sword!
He'll break it!
[effort grunts]
That was a strong headbutt.
[TANJIRO] Damn you!
Let go of me!
No good.[straining]
I can't get him
to loosen his grip.
[water splashing]
[grunts softly]
Mr. Giyu!
[Giyu sighs]
You're starting
to get on my nerves.
Thanks to you,
my back is killing me now.
I'm not fond of being hurled
like a rag doll.
I'm gonna make you pay.
♪
Personally, I'd rather not draw
my sword if I can help it.
And I have a hard time
justifying using deadly force
if unnecessary.
But at this moment,
I'm against an opponent that
demands everything from me.
In the short time we fought,
my senses have been
pushed past their limits.
My dormant senses
have been rudely awakened
and are dragging me forward
towards the enemy.
I now know how much
it expands one's potential
to have one's back
against the wall
with their sword raised
in the face of death.
Mr. Giyu.
[♪ intense music playing]
[AKAZA] A mark appeared
and his movements have gotten...
Faster!
[GIYU] Water Breathing,
Fourth Form: Striking Tide!
[grunts softly, chuckles]
[grunts]
[TANJIRO] They're both so fast.
Mr. Giyu's speed increased
with the mark,
but Akaza adapted to it
instantly.
Don't tell me
that's all you're capable of!
[Giyu groans angrily]
[both grunting]
Show me more!
Don't you dare hold back!
[GIYU]
Tenth Form: Constant Flux!
[yelling]
Seventh Form:
Drop Ripple Thrust!
Destructive Death: Disorder!
[TANJIRO] Mr. Giyu! Akaza!
Calm down!
[weapons clanging]
Think. Don't panic.
Whatever you do,
don't lose focus.
[grunts]
Why is it that Akaza's attacks
are always so accurate?
How is he able to respond
to attacks from his blind spots?
Think!
[AKAZA] Your fighting spirit
has been tempered
like quality steel.
Your name?
[gasps]
[TANJIRO]
Back when he fought Mr. Rengoku,
I remember Akaza using the words
"fighting spirit."
What did he mean by that?
Is he able to sense things
through fighting spirit?
The same way I can sense things
through scent?
Wherever the enemy's aiming at,
I get this weird
tingling feeling.
So, that's how you knew Gyutaro
was attacking you from behind.
You sure are incredible,
Inosuke.
[laughs boisterously]
Well, my skin is tougher
than most people's.
And whether
it's from behind or not,
if someone's looking at me,
I know just
where they're lookin'.
Could you show me?
[laughs] Sure thing!
[determined grunt]
- It's my right shoulder.
- [gasps]
You really got it.
That's amazing!
It's even easier to know
someone's looking at me
if they had killing intent.
Since anyone who can harm me
is bad news,
killing intent kind of
feels like it's stabbing me
through the skin, you know?
[TANJIRO] That's right.
Inosuke was able
to sense the invisible
using only his honed
sense of touch.
Think back.
What else did we talk about...
that day?
Where things get real tricky
is when someone who doesn't have
killing intent or hostility
is looking at me,
- like that tiny hag!
- Huh?
[INOSUKE] That old hag
from the house
with the wisteria mark
was sneaky.
Before I knew it...
Huh?
...she'd be sitting right
behind me holding rice balls.
Calling her a "hag" isn't nice.
She's elderly.
- Elderly hag!
- Stop that!
Well, that got me thinkin'.
If I could hide my killing
intent, then I'd be a ninja.
I'd be able to sneak up
on anybody.
- [chuckles excitedly]
- Sure.
But, Inosuke,
she was only sneaky
'cause she didn't have
the intent of harming you.
And I think beheading a demon
without killing intent
would be impossible.
[INOSUKE] Hmm.
Yeah, you're probably right.
A half-hearted strike
without any killing intent
would never be strong enough
to cut through a demon's neck.
[TANJIRO]
It was a casual conversation
but I think Inosuke
was on to something.
What is it that
Akaza supposedly senses?
What does he mean
by "fighting spirit"?
Is it killing intent?
Is it the will to fight?
The time spent training?
Or maybe the amount?
Is it like the way
I can anticipate movements
through scent?
There must be something I can do
to disrupt his compass!
[♪ rock music playing]
Hinokami Kagura: Dance!
Just one problem
with your attack.
You're wide open!
[TANJIRO] His fist!
[grunts]
[panting]
Fighting spirit.
Instincts. Compass.
Perception.
Striking with killing intent.
Sensing the invisible.
Executing the impossible.
I see.
So, that's it.
- [birds chirping]
- [leaves rustling]
[laughter]
Um, Father?
What do you think about
when you dance
the Hinokami Kagura?
If it's too tiring for you,
I can take your place next year.
I don't want you
to overwork yourself.
Thank you, Tanjiro.
But to be honest,
I haven't found the Kagura
to be the least bit tiring
over the last few years.
I can't quite explain it,
but back when I learned it
from your grandfather years ago,
even though I was younger,
healthier and stronger than now,
I found it to be
far more tiring back then.
[♪ poignant music playing]
[TANJIRO] For generations,
the Kagura was performed
by the Kamado family
at the start of each year.
It was an exhausting performance
that would last
from sunset till dawn.
There are 12 different forms
that must be repeated
over and over again,
thousands of times
before daybreak.
I think my exhaustion
was the result
of unnecessary movement.
Using the correct movements
and breathing patterns
are vital to the dance.
It's what allows you
to produce maximum strength
while using minimal actions.
Once you've mastered
your breathing and movement,
your mind will become
transparent.
Transparent?
But before any of that,
you must memorize
the moves of the dance
and slowly ingrain them
into your muscle memory.
In doing so,
you'll open up your five senses
and become aware
of the shape of your own body,
vessel by vessel.
That was the truly
strenuous part.
All you can think is that
even if you go on struggling,
you'll never succeed.
After you've learned
all these things
and committed them to memory,
you'll understand how to remove
what you don't need,
only leaving behind in your body
what is required of you,
closing off the rest.
Closing?
You know how people
often close their eyes
when they're trying
to hear better?
In that same way,
you'll pick out the things
you need the most
in the movement
while eliminating the rest.
Eventually, you will be able
to open and close the vessels
and muscles in your body,
as if it were second nature.
The same way you blink
without a second thought.
When that happens,
a path illuminated
by a bright light will open.
If your mind is as clear
as possible, you'll begin to see
the Transparent World
before you.
But this domain
can only be reached
by pushing yourself
past your limits,
despite the suffering
that may be required.
Will I ever get to see it?
If you work tirelessly,
then that's for you to decide.
There. All done.
[TANJIRO] Thank you.
Ten days before my father died,
an incident where a bear
began attacking people
happened on
a neighboring mountain.
We lit bonfires around the house
and set up multiple ropes
lined with bells.
Hmm?
[TANJURO] Tanjiro.
[TANJIRO] Yes, Father?
[TANJURO] Come with me.
[Tanjiro grunting, panting]
[grunts]
[breathing unsteadily]
[♪ dramatic sting]
[loud growling]
[TANJURO] I understand
you must be very hungry.
But I'm afraid I can't allow you
to come any closer.
If anyone were to try
and cause harm to my family,
I would be forced
to show you no mercy.
If you disregard this warning...
...I'll have no choice
but to take your life.
- [roaring]
- [bells tinkling]
[thuds]
[gasps]
[bells tinkling]
[TANJIRO] The bear's head that
was as thick as a human torso
dropped to the ground
with the sound of the bells.
My eyes couldn't follow it.
But if I'm not mistaken,
my father slashed it twice
in the blink of an eye.
He must have.
His ax wouldn't have been
able to cut through otherwise.
All the while,
my father's scent never wavered.
Before and after
beheading the bear,
he emitted no fear,
no killing intent.
I hope that you were watching.
A day might come
where you have to do the same.
[wind blowing]
[TANJIRO] My father
wasn't the type of person
to flaunt his strength.
I realized later on,
that night, he wanted me
to see it in action.
The movements necessary
to be able to see
the Transparent World
he spoke of.
I'm sure my father, grandfather,
and great-grandfather
all learned the same way.
Whatever you do, never give up.
Always stay calm and focused.
Any wall you come up against
can be shattered
if you just work tirelessly.
[TANJIRO] I understand, Father.
In that moment...
that's why I was able to dodge
Akaza's inescapable blow
to my side.
If I hadn't moved in time,
I'm positive that strike
would have killed me.
When I was alternating moves
with Mr. Giyu,
weaving my attacks
in between each of his,
I was protected from being hit
by those lethal blows.
But in that instant,
even Mr. Giyu
couldn't make it in time.
However, for whatever reason,
I knew dodging was possible.
And for just a split second,
I was able to see it.
That world.
[♪ enchanting music playing]
The Transparent World.
Even his body
started to look transparent.
The same is when Hantengu
was hiding inside his own heart.
I don't know
if I saw him or smelled him.
Dodge.
I used only the senses
that would let me do that.
Without thinking, my body
moved faster than ever before.
When I'm inside the Transparent
World my father spoke of,
my battle instincts
improve drastically.
I can see my opponent's lungs
and the blood moving
throughout their body.
I can see
my own muscles contracting
faster and clearer than before.
If I close off
the fighting spirit
that Akaza
must be detecting me with,
I can go for his neck.
[screeches]
[TANJIRO] See it.
See it!
[exhales]
[♪ rock music playing]
It looks like
you've thrown about
every last Water Form at me.
Enough is enough,
wouldn't you say?
I'm putting an end to this.
But you have my respect
for lasting so long!
[GIYU] What?
In the middle of my downswing...
...he hit it from the side.
And snapped my sword!
- Goodbye, Giyu.
- [impact grunts]
[flesh squelching]
[muted silence]
[thuds]
[♪ intense dramatic music
playing]
- [exhales]
- [flame roaring]
[GIYU] He stopped the attack
by cutting off his fist.
His breathing is different.
And his appearance...
I've been saved by Tanjiro.
[AKAZA]
All of the cells in my body
down to the ones in my hair
are screaming at me to kill him
as soon as possible.
I don't know what kind of change
he underwent, but...
...he's dangerous.
[GIYU] His focus is on Tanjiro.
Now's my chance.
[AKAZA] Technique Development,
Final Form:
Blue Silver Chaotic Afterglow!
[GIYU] His attack speed
boosted again,
and the force is increased.
My only chance now
is with Dead Calm!
[TANJIRO] This must be
what Father was talking about.
This is it.
The Transparent World.
Strange. It feels like
time is passing by so slowly.
Or maybe... their movements
just look slower now.
[♪ intense music continues]
[groans]
[GIYU] It's no use.
A hundred strikes at once
is unavoidable.
Even with Dead Calm,
I still wasn't able
to block all of them.
[AKAZA] Stand proud, Giyu.
Most wouldn't have been
able to survive that.
You must have evaded
my fatal blows.
There's no need for you to die
like Kyojuro and Tanjiro did.
Give up your pride
and become a demon, Giyu.
[GIYU] Tanjiro's behind him
and he hasn't noticed?
- [Akaza speaking indistinctly]
- Is he masking his presence?
Now's our chance!
Tanjiro, do it!
If you have the strength,
behead him.
Before he notices you,
go for it!
Akaza!
Prepare to be decapitated!
[AKAZA] Huh?
[GIYU] He willingly
gave himself away!
[AKAZA] He's still alive?
I never would have thought
someone like him
could survive
an attack like that.
Well, it doesn't matter.
After all, my Destructive Death,
Compass Needle
can detect any attack!
The stronger my opponent's
fighting spirit is,
the greater
my Compass Needle's reaction.
[quivers]
What is this?
What is this odd presence
he's emitting?
It feels like
he's turned himself
into some other creature.
It's like...
...his fighting spirit is gone.
But how?
I have to calm down. Focus!
[grunts]
[flame roaring]
[TANJIRO] Hinokami Kagura:
Setting Sun Transformation.
[♪ intriguing music playing]
[tinkling]
[gasps]
[Akaza straining]
This can't be possible.
[Tanjiro exhales]
[AKAZA] In the last
several hundred years,
I've never once seen a human
without any fighting spirit.
Even newborn children
had traces of it.
And yet, in that instant,
his fighting spirit vanished
as if it were never there
to begin with.
It's as if
I was facing an anomaly
that shouldn't even exist.
So, my senses
were thrown into confusion.
My Compass Needle
detected nothing.
[tinkling]
But that's not the biggest issue
at hand here.
When on the battlefield,
there's no telling
what could come your way.
It's vital that you're able
to deal with the unexpected
at a moment's notice.
And I'm able to do that!
Or at least... I thought so.
But during that short battle,
he was able to grasp something
and use it to surpass my speed.
Whatever it was he learned
was able to shatter
centuries' worth
of martial arts techniques
with a single head-on attack.
Within those eyes of his,
there was no hatred, no rage,
no killing intent
or fighting spirit.
He must have somehow seen
what I'd been looking for:
the domain that lies
within the realm of the highest.
None other than
the selfless state.
For some time now,
I've had a vague sense
that this state of mind existed.
And yet, even after
all these centuries,
I've yet to attain it.
[gasps]
[AKAZA] Not yet!
I can still fight!
I will continue
to become stronger!
[TANJIRO] This is bad.
He's reattaching his head!
[effort grunting]
- [thuds]
- [gasps]
[AKAZA] I can't die here.
Not like this.
I have to become stronger.
Stronger than anyone else
in the whole world!
Stronger!
- [thuds]
- [fizzles out]
I have to find a way
to become stronger.
[clatters]
[body thuds]
[TANJIRO] That's it. It's over.
We won!
[sighs in relief]
[grunts in pain]
So lightheaded.
My muscles are cramping up.
My body's reached its limit.
Tanjiro, are you all ri--
[gasps]
His body
hasn't disintegrated yet.
Does... Does this mean...
Tan--
[♪ intense music playing]
[grunts]
[TANJIRO] He's moving!
His body is still intact!
The severed part is closing up!
[strained grunting]
I can't see straight.
I can't.
[impact grunts]
[strained gasping]
No. No way.
Slashing his neck
didn't kill him!
Is there some kind of condition
like with Gyutaro and Daki?
That can't be it.
His head disintegrated,
yet he hasn't given up!
It's like he's trying to evolve!
[impact grunts]
If we don't do something,
his head will stop
being his weak point like Muzan!
This battle isn't over yet.
I have to fight...
Tanjiro!
He's fainted.
Of course he has.
He's long since
passed his limit.
[grunts]
Water Breathing, Fourth Form:
[♪ epic music playing]
Striking Tide!
Ridiculous!
He lost his head and can still
regenerate that quickly?
[sword clanking]
[grunting]
[yelling]
- [coughs]
- [blood splatters]
I can't hear out of my left ear,
and my right hand has gone numb.
I can still grip my sword,
but who knows for how long.
Wait!
I...
I'm here. I'm still alive!
If you wanna kill Tanjiro,
you'll have to defeat me first!
[AKAZA] An indomitable spirit.
It will never bend,
no matter what crisis
it finds itself in.
We don't fight the way
samurai do.
We don't carry weapons,
though we carry our convictions
like swords.
[MAN] Though we carry
our convictions like swords,
our battles are waged
with our fists.
[AKAZA] You are such an eyesore!
[soft thump]
[GIRL] Please stop.
[AKAZA] Who is that?
Mr. Hakuji,
please, that's enough!
[♪ poignant music playing]
[AKAZA] Let go.
Let go of my hand.
Just who are you?
Stop. You don't
have to keep going. [sniffles]
Let's leave this place together.
[AKAZA] I can't.
I've still got unfinished
business with those two.
[GIRL]
What do you mean by that?
[AKAZA]
I've got to become stronger.
I've got to!
I'll kill anyone
who gets in my way.
Why do you want that? [sniffles]
For what reason
do you need to become stronger?
[AKAZA] Because...
unless I'm strong enough,
I won't be able to bring
any more back home to him.
He needs medicine.
I must become stronger.
[grunts angrily]
If I don't, I won't be able to
get away with the money I stole.
If I happen to be caught,
I won't be able
to defend myself.
If I'm not strong enough,
the magistrate will catch me
and have me beaten and lashed.
[whipping]
[MAGISTRATE]
We've already given you
three tattoos on each arm
for stealing.
Next time,
we'll chop off your hand.
[Hakuji chuckling]
[laughing]
[ATTENDANT]
Bow your head and repent!
If you're gonna chop it off,
then do it!
Go ahead and take both of them
if you're really serious.
I'll just use my feet to steal.
You're not gonna catch me again,
so make it count!
[MAGISTRATE] To hear this from
someone at such a young age.
This boy of 11 has already
taken on punishments
that would make
a grown man faint.
You are a demon child!
Go and call me
whatever names you want.
"Demon child" suits me
just damn fine!
They say I already had teeth
when I was born,
so I guess I am.
- Be quiet!
- Dirty little punk!
[HAKUJI] Don't you mean
"demon child," you bastard?
[grunts]
Hmph!
SOUTH TOWN MAGISTRATE'S OFFICE
[birds calling]
[MAN 1] Hakuji!
[MAN 2] Oh! [panting]
There you are!
[voice breaking] When you were
caught for stealing again,
word about it made its way
back to your father.
He hung himself, Hakuji!
Huh?
[Hakuji's father weakly]
"Dear Hakuji,
live an honest life.
You can still start over."
- [wind blowing]
- [leaves rustling]
[♪ poignant music continues]
[paper fluttering]
[HAKUJI]
What kind of world is this?
Are the poor
not even allowed to live?
[voice breaking] Dad.
To hell with this rotten world.
To all of it![sobbing]
Every rotten human,
they can all burn in hell!
[grunts angrily]
Why do scumbags like them
get the privilege of living
when my father had to die
in such a horrible way?
He was never a burden to me.
So why would he feel that way?
You didn't do anything wrong,
Dad. You didn't!
I never cared
about getting beaten
after I was caught stealing.
Even if they beat me until every
bone in my body was broken,
I could take it all
for you, Dad.
For centuries even.
Learn your lesson!
Live an honest life!
[HAKUJI] Why don't you
shut the hell up, you scumbag?
Medicine's expensive.
The hell do you expect me
to do about that?
My dad's only getting thinner
and thinner by the day.
He's so malnourished,
you can see his bones.
I just want him to have
something better to eat.
I would have happily
given my life...
[voice breaking]
...if it meant saving his.
I'd have done anything...
for my father!
[breathing heavily]
- [clapping]
- Huh?
SORYU
[MAN] Well, well.
I am quite impressed.
I was called over
because someone said that
a child was about to be killed.
But you've laid out seven
grown-ups with your bare fists.
You've got some talent,
don't ya?
Not just anyone can take on
that many guys and still win.
[chuckling] That's the kind of
spunk I like to see.
[AKAZA] What's going on here?
Who is this man?
Could these be my memories?
How about you join my dojo?
I don't have any students
at the moment.
Stay out of my way,
you old fart!
You lookin' to die?
- Those tattoos.
- Uh?
You're a criminal from Edo.
I'm guessing
after being thrown out,
you eventually
found your way here.
I never asked for your opinion.
Now shut up
and get the hell out of my way!
[scoffs] All right.
Time to be reborn!
You ready?
That's it. Drop dead, old man!
[grunting]
[impact grunts]
[strained grunt, coughs, gasps]
[body thuds]
SORYU
[MAN] I'll give it to you.
You're tough.
DOJO
After that beating I gave you,
you came to
in less than an hour.
The name's Keizo.
I teach
the Soryu style of fighting
which uses only your bare hands.
Like I said, I don't have
any other students.
So I get by by doing whatever
odd jobs I can for people.
I have a daughter
who's in rather poor health.
I'd like you
to help look after her.
I'd be here if I could,
but I have to work.
My wife was pushed
to the edge of exhaustion
and drowned herself.
Life sure takes a bite
out of you, doesn't it?
If I were a more capable man,
my wife and daughter wouldn't
have suffered like this.
You said you knew
I was a criminal.
Are you really all right leaving
your daughter around me?
Why wouldn't I be?
I pummeled the criminal
out of you earlier, didn't I?
It's fine.
[♪ tender music playing]
[AKAZA] They are alike.
I get it now.
The reason
you disgusted me earlier.
It was because you would've
dredged up memories
of my worthless past.
[KEIZO]
This is my daughter, Koyuki.
[coughing]
[AKAZA] My worthless past.
Worthless.
[coughing]
Hakuji, I'm so sorry.
[chuckles] How are you feeling?
[coughing]
You okay being up?
[KOYUKI] Hmm.
Looks like you've got more color
in your cheeks this morning.
[chuckles] That's good.
Hmm.
- Huh?
- Oh, yeah. This boy.
His name is... [chuckles]
Well, I've asked him countless
times, and he won't say.
- Go on, get inside.
- [grunts]
Have a seat.
I wanna know his name
when I get back. Okay?
Um...
Your... Your face.
You're hurt.
Are you all right?
[AKAZA] "I'll make you better.
I'll save you.
Protect you."
In that past life, all I did
was spew a bunch of lies.
I was so pathetic.
[birds chirping]
[coughing]
Oh, thank you.
[HAKUJI] You don't have to
thank me every time, you know.
Just focus on resting.
I'm sorry for causing you
trouble like this.
It's fine. Really.
Koyuki, you want this closed?
Hmm. You can leave it open.
[HAKUJI] Koyuki was very
delicate and frail.
I would change out her towels
and nightgown and give her water
even throughout the night.
And whenever she needed
to use the lavatory,
obviously she was too weak
to be able to go
without needing assistance.
I was used to taking care
of the sick because of my dad,
and since I had an almost
inhuman physical endurance,
it really wasn't a big deal
for me.
[crows cawing]
Sorry to make you help me
all day.
[HAKUJI] Why do people
who are suffering from illness
always feel the need to say
they're sorry?
"Sorry to make you
do things for me."
"Sorry if my coughing's
bothering you."
"Sorry I can't put food
on the table like I should."
They didn't choose
to have to live this way.
Of course
they wanna breathe normally.
They can't help it
if they start coughing.
Out of everyone,
they're the ones
suffering the most.
Sorry again to make you do this.
Because of my sickness,
you're not able to do
your training,
or even go out and have fun.
[HAKUJI]
I don't care about having fun.
I never have.
As far as training goes,
I squeeze it in whenever I can,
so, it's fine.
Are you sure?
Even you need to take
a little break.
I hear there are fireworks
happening tonight.
You should go see them.
Fireworks, huh?
If you don't feel nauseous
at night,
I could carry you on my back
and go see them on the bridge.
Huh?
If you're not feeling up to it,
they'll do fireworks again
next year, and after that.
So, we can just go
when you're better.
[crying softly]
There was one thing
that was hard
about taking care of her.
And that was whenever she would
suddenly break out into tears
in the middle
of our conversations.
I can imagine how she felt,
bedridden and sick as she was,
but it still made me
uncomfortable.
[insects trilling]
SORYU
[impact grunts, wheezes]
[sighs] Ah, now I understand.
The symbol used for Hakuji,
it's the same as komainu.
[chuckles] That makes sense.
You and I really are the same,
after all.
We only thrive when we have
something to protect.
Just like the komainu
who protect the entrance
to the shrines. [chuckles]
[laughs heartily]
[♪ gentle music playing]
[HAKUJI] There was a story as to
how my master owned this land,
even though he wasn't a samurai
or anything like that.
He had rescued an elderly man
from a group of bandits.
The old man,
who had no living heirs,
was so impressed
by his Soryu technique
that he left him
not only his land,
but the dojo that lay upon it.
However, there were those
with envious eyes
who wished to have the land
and dojo all to themselves.
The Kenjutsu Dojo next door
started harassing
the Soryu Dojo.
Because of that,
the Soryu Dojo had a hard time
keeping any students.
But now, thanks to my training
here and caring for Koyuki...
...my heart has finally
found salvation.
[effort grunting]
[chuckles]
Three short years went by
and I turned 18.
Koyuki was 16.
She was almost never
bedridden anymore
and was now able
to live a normal life.
[chuckles]
[birds chirping]
Hakuji! Come here.
Yes, sir.
[insects trilling]
This dojo,
would you be willing
to take it over for me, Hakuji?
Koyuki's told me that
she's quite fond of you as well.
[exclaims in surprise]
[HAKUJI] As someone branded
with the tattoos of a criminal,
picturing any kind of future
for myself was hard enough.
But a future in which someone
could like a person like me?
I couldn't have even dreamed it.
My dad asked me
to lead an honest life,
something I never thought
was possible.
But perhaps it really is.
The faint hope
of being able to start over
began to swell within me
until it felt like
it was about to burst.
[♪ tender music playing]
But I could never have predicted
in that moment
that the two people
I wanted to protect
more than anything else
in this life...
...would end up
meeting the fate they did.
I had made a trip to Edo
to visit my dad's grave.
I wanted to let him know
that I was getting married.
I returned before even a full
day and night had passed.
Yet a sense of dread
came over me.
My chest started to feel tight
and a terrible feeling of nausea
overtook me.
[retches]
[MAN] Someone put poison
in the well!
[voice breaking]
The other school was so angry
they couldn't beat you
or Mr. Keizo,
they went and did this
out of spite!
It's atrocious. Unthinkable!
They even killed Koyuki!
[HAKUJI] Why?
Why is it whenever the ones I
care about are in mortal peril,
I'm never there for them?
[fireworks bursting in distance]
[crickets chirping]
I had even gone
and made a promise to her.
Are you sure
that I'm the one for you?
When we were children,
do you remember
when you talked to me
about seeing the fireworks?
- Huh? Uh... no, not really.
- [giggles softly]
Because of those little talks
we used to have,
there were a lot of things
which I took with me
that gave me hope
for the future.
You said even if we couldn't see
the fireworks that year,
we could go to the one
happening next year,
or the year after that.
The truth is,
I could never imagine a future
where I'd still be alive
a year later,
and certainly not
any longer than that.
My mother couldn't either.
I think that's why she ended up
taking her own life,
'cause she didn't
want to see me die.
Not just her.
I could tell my father
had given up hope, too,
deep down inside.
Because I was just so weak.
But you never treated me
that way.
You were able to see
a future for me.
You talked to me about
doing things as if...
As if it were obvious
that I'd still be here.
[crying softly]
That made me so very happy.
So, yes, I am sure
you're the one for me.
Would you...
Would you be my husband?
[distant explosion]
[fireworks bursting]
Yes.
I promise to become stronger
than anyone,
and protect you
for the rest of my life.
[exclaims]
[HAKUJI]
In the end, I was all talk.
I wasn't able to fulfill
any of my promises.
[chuckles]
[♪ foreboding music playing]
What do you want? [gasps]
You've got some nerve.
Wait. You're from the Soryu--
[screaming]
[♪ somber music playing]
[man grunts]
[Hakuji grunts, yells]
[groans angrily]
The family, the Soryu Dojo,
were recently poisoned.
And we believe
that a student of theirs
retaliated against
the Kenjutsu Dojo.
Sixty-seven people
were murdered inside.
He shattered their skulls
and crushed their organs,
all barehanded.
Not only were most of the bodies
mangled and mutilated
beyond recognition,
most had limbs missing
that we couldn't even locate.
Organs, limbs, brain matter,
even jaws and eyeballs
were found
strewn across the walls
and the ceiling of the premises.
This killer
was no ordinary human.
[wet squelching]
[breathing shakily]
[MUZAN] I heard
there was some commotion
about a demon sighting here,
even though I know
I never sent one.
So, I decided to come
see for myself.
Yet all I find is a human.
How utterly disappointing.
[HAKUJI] Move, or I'll kill you!
- [thuds]
- [splatters]
It just so happens
I was contemplating
creating 12 powerful demons.
I wonder if you'll be
able to withstand
the amount of blood
I'm about to give you.
You... [grunts]
...do whatever you want.
None of it matters.
[thunder rumbling]
[♪ somber music playing]
[grunting]
[AKAZA] After becoming a demon,
I lost my memories...
and once again,
started to seek out power.
- [thuds]
- [grunts]
- [flesh squelches]
[clangs]
- [wet squelching]
- [sword clatters]
It's not enough!
It will never be enough!
[thunderclap]
Even though I had nothing
left to my name.
worth fighting for anymore.
Even though my family
was no longer around
and I had no desire
to live in a world without them.
For over a century,
I committed senseless massacres
over and over again.
Thinking about it now,
it's pathetic.
It's absurd.
All those deaths
were meaningless.
Even if I died now,
I couldn't go where the other
three were waiting for me.
Damn you for dredging up
these memories. You bastard!
Pathetic humans,
clinging on to life
with their fragile bodies!
Even their strongest
eventually die
and vanish into thin air!
[flesh squelching]
[GIYU] He's still not dead?
You can't be serious.
I have to kill him
before it's too late.
If we let him regenerate,
there will be no stopping him.
- [loud thump]
- [gasps]
[grunts] I must have passed out.
What's going on?
His head's back!
But how is that even possible?!
I decapitated him!
[♪ intense music playing]
Destructive Death:
Annihilation Type.
Stop it!
[AKAZA] Seriously?
He can still move?
[TANJIRO] Mr. Giyu and I
are going to win!
Akaza, I'll behead you
as many times as it takes!
My sword!
[GIYU] It slipped
out of his hands.
[TANJIRO] I lost my grip.
[effort grunts]
[KEIZO] All right, young man.
Time to be reborn.
[AKAZA] I despise
those who are weak.
Weaklings... Instead of
fighting you fair and square,
they always resort
to cheap tricks.
They're atrocious.
They have no patience.
And they quickly grow desperate.
Just thinking about them
makes me sick.
I killed people
with my fists for protection.
I desecrated my master's
beloved Soryu with blood.
And I couldn't follow
my father's last wishes!
That's right.
The one I wanted to kill...
[clatters]
[TANJIRO] This couldn't be
worse. I dropped my sword!
[♪ foreboding music playing]
My fists aren't enough
to stop him!
He's about to unleash
the Annihilation Type move
he used on Mr. Rengoku!
I've got to take Mr. Giyu
with me out of the attack range!
[GIYU] Leave me! Save yourself!
[AKAZA] I've got to kill...
...that weakling
I've come to hate!
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[thudding]
[grunts, gasps]
[flesh squelching]
[blood spurts]
[TANJIRO]
He just attacked himself.
Why would he turn on himself
like that?
Why?
[♪ melancholic music playing]
For a second,
I could pick up the scent
of gratitude from him.
Why did he smile at me?
[AKAZA] That's enough! Stop it!
I don't want to regenerate!
Don't you get it?
The battle is over!
In that decisive moment, I lost.
That technique
he beheaded me with
was nothing short of perfection.
He anticipated my movements
and pivoted at the last second,
then struck me down before
I could unleash my attack.
It's over now.
Let me accept my fate
and go to hell.
[TANJIRO]
Where's he trying to go?
[gasps softly]
He stopped in his tracks.
[HAKUJI] Dad.
Are you feeling better now?
Are you in pain anymore?
No need to worry, son. I'm fine.
Thank you, Hakuji.
I'm sorry, Father.
I'm sorry I couldn't start over
like you wanted.
I failed you.
[KEIZO] Do not despair.
Regardless of
who you grow up to be,
you're still my son
and still my student.
Heaven may not accept you...
...but you needn't worry.
Our hearts will be with you.
Master.
[gasps]
Didn't you say you were seeking
to become stronger than anyone?
Don't tell me you intend
to let it end like this, Akaza.
[AKAZA] That's right.
I can't die here.
I have to get stronger!
So what if I got beheaded?
Who cares
if I win or lose the fight?
If I kill those
who stand in my way...
then there's still hope
for me to get stronger!
I made a promise!
I'm not about to break it!
[breathing shakily]
[♪ tender music playing]
Mr. Hakuji,
thank you so much.
You've done more than enough.
It's okay.
We're all right now.
Akaza!
[♪ epic cinematic music playing]
[wailing]
Sorry!
I'm sorry
I couldn't protect you!
I wasn't there
when you needed me to be!
I couldn't keep
a single promise I made.
I'm sorry. [sobbing] Please
try to forgive me, Koyuki.
I'm so sorry.
[continues sobbing]
I'm so happy you remembered us.
I can't tell you
how happy that makes me.
And to see you now
as the man that I once knew,
I'm so grateful.
Welcome home, Hakuji.
Hey, Hakuji.
Welcome home.
[HAKUJI] I'm back now.
I'm finally back home.
Welcome back home...
...my darling.
[gasps softly]
[♪ gentle music playing]
[Tanjiro breathing shakily]
He vanished.
[gasps]
[inhales deeply]
[exhales sharply]
It's over. Right?
Gotta hurry...
...and get to where
Ms. Tamayo is.
And then...
[grunts weakly] Tanjiro.
[exhales]
[Kasugai Crow cawing]
Tanjiro! Giyu!
Have defeated Upper Three!
They are unable to stay
conscious due to exhaustion!
They've passed out!
Tanjiro! Giyu!
Have defeated Upper Three!
Upper Three!
[♪ haunting
choral music playing]
[KOKUSHIBO] Akaza!
His presence has vanished.
What a baffling conclusion.
Akaza...
...what happened to your burning
ambition to defeat me?
To think you'd abandoned
everything you stood for...
...and turned your back
on the path to greatness.
[♪ music intensifies]
Your weakness appalls me.
Huh?
[exclaims]
This feeling.
Could Lord Akaza be dead?
Very strange.
Surely my imagination
must be running wild, right?
It almost felt like Lord Akaza
had turned into some creature.
But now that he's dead,
I guess it doesn't matter.
- [laughs]
- [rattling]
Let's see,
where was I?
Oh, I remember.
I had just asked for your name,
hadn't I?
[Kanao breathing shakily]
[KASUGAI CROW] Tanjiro! Giyu!
Have defeated Upper Three!
Upper Three!
Did you hear that?
Yes. Excellent work, Tomioka.
Excellent work, Kamado.
[♪ closing theme song playing]
Mr. Tomioka and Tanjiro.
They did it!
[IGURO] Now it's our turn
to follow their lead.
Right!
[demon snarling]
Hang in there, Agatsuma!
[cawing]
[INOSUKE] Start flapping
those wings faster,
or I'm gonna keep poking!
You're gonna use those wings
to show me where
the strongest demon is!
You hear me?
I'm coming through!
Hyah!
Now we're talkin'!
I'm sensing a powerful
demon over here.
[cawing]
Where is Big Brother?
Where are all the Upper Ranks?
Tell me! Come on!
I'm gonna bury you all!
[KANATA] The passageway
leading north
on the 88th level is clear.
No sign of Muzan.
[KUINA]
The 100th and 27th levels
in the southeast are clear.
No sign of Muzan.
He's in here.
He has to be.
But where is he?
[KANATA] There's no sign
of Muzan on any of the levels
from 90 to 100, either.
[KUINA] Covering the entire
100th and 33rd levels.
No sign of Muzan.
Our crows will find you.
You can only hide from us
for so long.
We'll search every inch
of this Infinity Castle.
Even if you try to run from us,
we will hunt you down.
[plucking]
FOUR
[continues plucking
biwa strings]
Multi-layered structures
are headed northeast.
Attention! The castle's
expanding in every direction.
Folding over themselves!
[Nakime plucking
biwa strings faster]
[BOTH] And becoming one!
[gasps] You can't be serious.
No.
It's fine.
We've come too far to lose.
Crows, push forward,
and find Muzan!
[MUZAN] Try all you want,
Demon Slayers!
But each one of you
will meet your end
before ever reaching me!
You may be feeling smug after
beheading one of my Upper Ranks,
but unless you could kill me,
your triumph is meaningless!
[laughs maliciously]
You're all going to die
the most pointless deaths
all the while
never seeing my face!
I can't think of a more fitting
end for the Demon Slayer Corps.
Mark my words.
When I'm done here,
I'm going to make you regret
the day you were born!
Just wait.
You're each going to squirm
and writhe in pain.
Draw your final breaths
because for every one
of you Demon Slayers,
there is no tomorrow!
[KASUGAI CROW 1] Please, Giyu.
Don't die!
[KASUGAI CROW 2] We can't
have you dying on us, Tanjiro.
[music ends]
[♪ closing theme song playing]
[song ends]
Downloaded from MoviesMod.at